화이트칼라 지난 이야기..
Previously on White Collar...
우리의 최고이자 마지막 목표를 위하여
To our best and final score...
이게 뭔가?
What is it?
독일 유보트에서 나온
부분 적하목록 입니다
Part of the original German u-boat
manifest.
아직도 카프리가 미술품을
가지고 있다고 생각하시나요?
You still think Caffrey has the art?
모르겠어
I don't know.
누가 훔쳤든 간에
이 목록에서 하나라도
Whoever stole it,
if a single item on this list
- 나타난다면..
- 잡을 수 있죠
shows up anywhere --
We got 'em.
그래. 잡을 수 있어
Yeah. We got 'em.
금고는 찾았어?
Did you find the safe?
목록은 여기에 없어, 모즈
미안해
The manifest wasn't in there,
Moz. I'm sorry.
왜 그래, 새라
내가 누군지 항상 알고 있었잖아
Oh, come on, Sara,
you've always known who I am.
그래, 네 말이 맞아
Yeah, you're right.
내가 말하려던게 어떤건지
알아냈나보네
I guess you figured out
everything I have to offer.
카프리, 제발 몸 조심하구..
Caffrey, please take care
of yourself.
반 다이크의 "소년의 초상"
Van Dyck --
"Portrait of a Boy."
어디 있니
Where are you?
여기 있네
There it is.
드가의 "가면 쓴 무용수들"
Degas -- "Masked Dancers."
Oh, come on.
모즈, 팔지 않아서 정말 다행이네
Moz, thank God
you didn't sell it.
- 안녕
- 그들이 보물에 대해 알고있어
- Hey.
- They know about the treasure.
우리가 물망에 오를꺼야
They're on to us.
무슨 말 하는거야?
무슨 일인데?
What are you talking about?
What happened?
"히틀러 복제품이 있는
유령선이 발견됬다"
"Ghost ship found
with Hitler clones"?
"값 비싼 미술품들과 함께"
"And priceless art."
- 우리의 값 비싼 미술품들 말야
- 오
Our priceless art.
Ooh, ooh.
"채식주의 뱀파이이어가
지역 정원을 망친다"도 있는데
They're also on to
a vegan vampire
ravaging community gardens.
너무 당황할 필요는 없다니까
Look, there's no need
to hit the panic button.
닐, 이건 우리 보물이
Neal, this is where
our treasure has reached
말콤 글래드웰이 말한
"티핑 포인트"에 도달한 것과 같아
what Malcolm Gladwell would call
a "tipping point."
검사에선 아무것도 안나왔어
요원님도 마찬가지고
Forensics doesn't talk,
nor does Peter.
그래, 하지만 요원님과 요원집단이
Yeah, but the suit
and his suit cohorts
DC 범죄국으로 가져갔잖아
그 중 한명은
brought in D.C. Art Crimes,
one of whom
호텔 바에서 '나치 콩'이라도
실수로 나오길 기대할거야
was willing to spill
the Nazi beans in a hotel bar.
그녀는 내가 인터폴이라고 생각할거야
Uh-huh.
She thought I was Interpol.
그게 바로 내 요점이라고
My point exactly.
알았어, 모즈
비밀은 영원히 지켜질 수 없지
I get it, Moz.
Secrets can't be kept forever.
하지만 그 누구도
우릴 추적하진 못할꺼야
But no one
can trace this to us.
드가를 사려고 했던 장물아비인
헤일을 제외하고 말이지
Except Hale, who I've already
lined up to fence the Degas.
오, 새라도 있네
Oh, and Sara,
갑자기 일을 망칠 수도 있는 사람이야
the half-suit who suddenly
broke things off.
오늘 만나러 갈꺼야
새라가 알고 있는게 뭔지 알아낼거고
I'm gonna see her today.
I'll find out what she knows.
넘겨 버려
그냥 지나 가자고
Skip it.
Let's just go.
- 잊어버려
- 그럴 필요는 없잖아
Vamonos.
We don't have the means.
우리가 드가를 판다면 달라
We will if we sell the Degas.
안돼. 그건 너무 위험해
No. That is
too high-profile.
FBI는 부분적인 목록만 가지고 있잖아
The FBI only has
a partial list.
드가가 거기 있을 확률은 아주 낮다고
The odds are miniscule
that the Degas is even on it.
그게 목록에 있는데, 팔게 되면
But if it is
and we sell it --
우리가 멀리 떠나고 난 후에
누군가 "드가는 넘어가자" 라고 말하겠지
We'll be long gone before anyone
can say "Degas away with it."
명심해, 우리가 어딜 가든간에
And wherever we go,
I am telling you,
FBI와 피터 요원님이 우리를
찾기 전까진 절대 멈추지 않을꺼야
the FBI, Peter, will not stop
until they find us.
그 목록을 얻기 전까진
떠날수 없어. 알겠어?
But we can't leave until we have
that list. All right?
나도 막대 사탕 만큼이나
문 따는 도구 좋아하는데
Much as I'd love
a candy-apple set of lock picks,
돌려 받고 싶을꺼라 생각했어
I thought you might
want this back.
고마워
Thank you.
더 이야기 하고 싶지만
회의에 늦어서 가봐야 돼
I'd love to catch up,
but I'm late for a meeting.
- 여권 때문이야?
- 아니
Was it the passports?
No, it wasn't.
그럼 뭐 때문이야?
Then what was it?
I know you, Sara.
새라, 네가 아무 이유 없이
그러진 않는다는 거 알아
You wouldn't have cut out like
that unless you had a reason to.
그래, 좋아
여권 때문이야
Okay, fine.
It was the passports.
훌륭하게 위조된 신분증을 보고나니
You had brilliantly
forged I.D.s,
네가 사기꾼이라는게 분명해졌어
and it dawned on me --
you're a con man.
- 만족해?
- 아니
Are you happy?
No.
사실을 말해줘
I want the truth.
닐..
난 보물을 봤어
Neal...
I saw the treasure.
내게 숨겨온 그걸
노트북에서 봤다고
I saw it on your laptop.
You hid it from me.
피터 요원님과 FBI에 숨겨왔던
그 보물 말야
You hid it from Peter, and
you're hiding it from the FBI.
그리고 이젠, 내가 입 다물고 있는지
확인하러 온거네
And now you're here to find out
if I'm gonna keep my mouth shut.
그렇게 냉정하게 생각하지 마
It's not as cold as that.
그래? 그럼 뭔데?
Really?
Then what is it?
사실대로 말해봐
Now you owe me the truth.
내게 잘가라고 말하려던거 아니었어?
Were you gonna say
goodbye to me?
아니
No.
- 새라
- 뭐?
Sara.
What?!
나랑 같이 갈래?
Would you have come with me?
내가 너랑 같이 가야해?
Would I have come with you?
어떻게 되는 건데?
How would that have worked?
그냥 떠나면 돼
We'd just go.
우리 발 밑의 온 세상을 버리고?
The whole world at our feet?
네게 가까이 가서 물어보려고 했었어
I came so close to asking you.
하지만 그러지 않았잖아
But you didn't.
아냐
No.
그게 내 답변이야
Well, then,
there's your answer.
새라
Sara.
닐이 왜 전화 안받는지 알겠구만
This explains why Neal
isn't picking up his phone.
음..
Well...
전 닐이 범죄 문제를 해결해야 하는
임무를 가진게 싫네요
I would hate to keep Neal
from his crime-solving duties.
잘 지내, 새라
Take care, Sara.
피터 요원님 만나서 반가웠어요
It's good to see you, Peter.
나도
You too.
개인적으로 절 찾아 오시다니
You've come to collect me
in person.
물어보기 망설여지지만, 왜죠?
I'm hesitant to ask, but why?
매튜 켈러에 대한 소식을 들었어
We got word on Matthew Keller.
매튜 켈러
닐의 전 파트너였지
Matthew Keller --
Neal's ex-partner.
좀 과장됐는데요
That's stretching it.
다들 알다시피, 작년에
켈러는 감옥에서 탈출했다
As most of you know, last year,
Keller broke out of prison
최고 보안 시설로 이송중에 말이지
during his transfer
to a maximum-security facility.
그리고 요원님을 납치 했었죠
He also arranged
to have you kidnapped.
그래, 기억나
불행히도 그 후로 또 달아났지
I remember that.
Unfortunately, he got away then.
하지만 이번주에
흔적이 잡혔어
But up until this week,
his trail was cold.
존스?
Jones?
이집트의 보안카메라 화면에서
켈러가 최근에 발견 되었습니다
Keller recently turned up
on some security footage
in Egypt.
보아하니, 사회 분쟁 지역에 가서
이득을 보고 있는것 같아
Apparently,
he's been taking advantage
of the political unrest
in the region.
다른 사람들과 경찰이
길거리에 나와 있는 동안
While the people and police
take to the streets,
값 비싼 박물관 작품들을
훔치는 거죠
he takes priceless pieces
from museums.
전형적인 켈러의 수법이네요
Classic Keller.
음, 이번에 켈러가 훔친건
Well, this time,
he did well for himself.
바로 이겁니다
He stole this --
You're looking at
3500년 된 특별한 부적이죠
a one-of-a-kind
3,500-year-old amulet.
나르메르의 무덤에 있었던
(Narmer : 이집트 제1왕조의 파라오)
Once in the tomb
of Narmer the First.
잃어버린 파라오의 부적이네요
The amulet of the lost pharaoh.
이집트 정부는 그 무엇과도 대체 할 수 없는
국가의 보물로 여기고 있지
The new Egyptian government
considers it a national treasure
and, obviously, irreplaceable.
켈러가 그 쪽으로 간
단서가 있나요?
Do we have any leads
on where Keller may be?
수사망을 빠져나갔지만, 이집트 인들은
맨하탄으로 밀수됬다고 믿고 있어
He's off the grid again,
but the Egyptians believe
the amulet's been smuggled
into Manhattan.
사무국에서는 부적을 찾아
돌려 주길 원해
The bureau wants us
to find it and return it.
켈러가 연루되어 있으니
정말 조심해야 한다
We exercise extreme caution,
given Keller's involvement.
그 놈이 우리 도시에 있으니
정의가 뭔지 보여주자고
He's in our city --
We bring him to justice.
닐, 얘기좀 하자
Neal, let's talk.
켈러가 관심 가지는게 뭐라고 생각해?
What do you think
Keller's up to?
금방 말하긴 어려운데요
It's too early to tell.
우리가 뭘 생각해 내더라도
Whatever we think he's doing,
벌써 세걸음 앞서 있을 거에요
he's probably
three steps past it by now.
왜 위험한 미국에서 거래를 하려 하지?
Why risk doing business
in the U.S.,
뉴욕에 있는 누군가와 말이야
with someone in New York?
그는 항상 뻔뻔하거든요
Oh, he's always been brazen.
음
Mm.
그들이 우리에게 관심있어 한다고 생각하나?
Think they're on to us?
켈러가 네게 연락했나?
Has Keller contacted you?
아니요. 왜요?
No. Why?
우리가 아무리 조심했어도
As hard as we've tried,
애들러의 잠수함에 일어난 일은
새어 나갔을거야
versions of what happened
to Adler's sub have leaked out.
그런 큰 비밀을 지킨다는건
어려운 일이죠
It's hard to keep
a secret that big.
맞아
Yeah.
켈러는 똑똑한 놈이야
Keller's a smart guy.
이런 소식들을 퍼트리기 시작했어
He starts putting
those rumors together...
요원님이 했던 생각과 같은 생각을
켈러가 하고 있는지 궁금하신거군요
You're wondering if he made
the same assumption you did.
네가 보물들을 가지고 있다고
켈러가 생각한다면
If he's thinking
you're in possession
1000억 달러의 가치가 있는 작품들은
구미를 당기기에 충분하지
of $1 billion
worth of lost artwork,
that's a reason
big enough to draw him back.
보물도, 너도 얻는거지
For it, and for you.
제가 보물을 훔쳤다고
그가 생각한다면
If he thinks
I stole the treasure,
그걸 써서 잡아버리죠
let's use it to take him down.
영어자막 : www.addic7ed.com (honeybunny)
한글자막 : EzLoves
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
블로그 : vstu77.blog.me
오타, 오역 등 피드백 남겨주세요!
WHITECOLLAR
S03E09 On the Fence
ORIGINAL DATE 2011/08/02
CREATED BY
JEFF EASTIN
도난당한 이집트 부적, 켈러와
뉴욕의 연관책을 찾았어
We found it --
the New York connection
between the Egyptian
stolen amulet and Keller.
잘됬네요. 아는 사람 있나요?
Great.
Anybody we know?
말해봐
You tell me.
이집트 사람들은 그 부적이
고대 문명 전문가인
The Egyptians believe
the shipment was sent
라켈 라로크라 불리는 사람에게
보내진 걸로 믿고 있어
to an ancient-civilizations
expert in Soho
named Raquel Laroque.
들어 본 이름이네요
이집트 학자에요
I know the name.
She's an egyptologist.
듣자하니, 그게 본업인 것 같더군
Apparently, that's her day job.
장물아비 인가요?
She's a fence?
죽여주는 실력이야
And a damn good one.
은폐 기술을 봐바
Check out
her concealment technique.
운반품을 이집트 선물가게에서 산
장난감 처럼 보이도록 했어
The shipments she gets
look like
Egyptian gift-shop tchotchkes.
하지만 실제론..
But in reality...
엑스레이에 발각되지 않는 틀로
값 비싼 유물을 둘러싸 놓았지
They're highly durable
X-ray-proof molds
built around real,
priceless artifacts.
미라의 귀환이군요
매력 있는데요
The mummy returns.
Sexy.
좋아 할 줄 알았어
Thought you might like that.
라로크는 복원 기술자를 찾고 있어
Ms. Laroque
has put out word
that she's in the market
for a restoration tech.
유물을 손상없이 꺼내기 위한
전문가가 필요한 거군요
She needs someone
to extract the artifacts
without damaging them.
꽤 도전적인 일인데요
It's challenging work.
음. 그걸 할 수 있는
사람을 알고 있나?
Mm. Know anyone
who can pull it off?
범죄 전문 친구들에게 말해서
할 수 있도록 해봐
Talk to your crime super-friends
and make it happen.
그 부적을 얻게 되면
켈러에게 한걸음 더 다가 갈 수 있어
We get this amulet,
we're one step closer to Keller.
네
All right.
라켈 라로크에 대해 아는거 있어?
Hey, what do you know
about Raquel Laroque?
이집트 학자라는 것 외엔 별로
Not much beyond
she's an egyptologist.
그녀가 '화끈하다' 라는건 들었어
I hear she's spicy.
무슨 의미야?
What does that mean?
나도 몰라. 내 정보가
별로 도움이 안되긴 하네
I don't know. Not all
my information's helpful.
헤일
Hale.
What's up, man?
오
Ooh!
모즈가 여기 이동식 사무실에
뭔가 작업해 줬다는걸 들었는데요
I heard Moz did some work
on your mobile office.
맞아, 아직 부가기능을 배우고 있는 중이지
Yeah, I'm still learning
all the bells and whistles.
모지가 설명서를 적어주는 건 거부해서 말야
Mozzie refuses to write down
instructions.
분명하게, 어떠한 공식적인
Obviously, we don't want
기록이라도 남기길 원하진 않아요
any public record
of our modifications.
난 네가 말해왔던 드가를
팔기 위해 대기중이야
I'll settle for that Degas
you keep promising.
가져올거에요, 조만간
It's coming. Soon.
작은 문제가 있거든요
Yeah, we had
a minor complication.
더 좋은걸 드리는건 어떨까요?
What if we could get you
something better?
음, 구매자가 드가에 빠져있거든
Well, my buyer has his heart set
on that Degas --
뭔가 진행하기 전에
Before we can move any of it,
혹시 라켈 라로크라는
장물아비를 아시나요?
do you know a fence
named Raquel Laroque?
알아
I do.
꽤 복합한 은폐 기술을
가지고 있지
She has this intricate
concealment technique.
네, 그게 바로 제가
이야기 해보고 싶은 부분이에요
Yeah, that's what I'd
like to talk to her about.
그녀는 복원 기술자를 찾고 있거든요
She's in the market
for a new restoration tech.
네가 그 일을 맡게 되면
If you get the job,
드가를 좀 더 빨리
얻을 수 있을까?
that will help eliminate
your delay with the Degas?
네, 닐을 보장해 주시면
더 신속히 처리하도록 할겁니다
Uh, yes. Uh, you vouch for Neal,
it will expedite the sale.
닐?
Neal?
그럴겁니다
It will.
좋아, 그럼
만남을 주선해보지
All right, then.
I'll set up a meeting.
꽤 늦는군
Your guy's very late.
나타날 거에요
헤일은 믿을만 하거든요
He'll show.
Hale is very reliable.
너랑 새라
You and Sara?
- 네, 저랑 새라요
- 끝난거야?
Yes. Me and Sara.
Over?
네
Yes.
그럼 내가 본건..
So what I witnessed...
가방 돌려 주려구요
Return of the breakup bag.
그래
All right.
무슨 일이 있었던거야?
What happened to you guys?
"그냥 우린 다른 사람이었다"
라는 말 말고 말야
And don't give me the "we're
just different people" routine.
우린 정말 다른 사람이었죠
We are very different people.
모두가 요원님과 엘리자베스 같진 않다구요
Not everybody can be
Peter and Elizabeth, okay?
말 나와서 말인데
헤일이 늦게 오니..
Ah, speaking of,
since Hale's running late --
응, 자기
잠복근무는 어때?
Hey, honey.
How's the stakeout going?
음, 사실 그것 때문에 전화한거야
Uh, that's why I'm calling.
예상 했던 것보다 더
길어질 것 같아서 말야
Looks like it's running
longer than expected.
안돼
Oh, no.
이런 말 하긴 싫지만, 오늘 저녁에
트레이와 쉐일라의 바베큐 파티엔 못갈 것 같아
I hate to say this,
but I don't think
we're gonna be able to make
Tray and Sheila's
barbecue tonight.
응, 정말 안됬네. 거의 나갈
준비 다 된 참이었거든
Wow, that's too bad, 'cause I
was ready to walk out the door.
물론 그랬을 거라 생각해
Aw, I'm sure you were.
트레이와 쉐일라를 못 견디거든
She can't stand
Tray and Sheila.
하지만, 나 없이 혼자 가도 돼
But, you know,
you could go without me,
물론 이미 차 마시면서
새 책을 보고 있지 않다면 말야
unless, of course,
you're already settled in
with a cup of tea
and a new book.
응, 잘 알겠어. 자기가 집에 오면
취소 해줄 거라는거는 의미란거 말야
I know thee well, as well,
which means
you're gonna make up
for canceling on me
when you get home, mister.
오, 자기야
듣고있는 사람 있는데
Oh, honey, do you know
you're on speaker?
오, 안녕 닐
Oh. Hi, Neal.
안녕하세요, 엘리자베스
Hi, Elizabeth.
좋아, 사건은 빨리 끝나는 거지?
All right, well,
crack this case soon, will you?
그럴 겁니다
둘 다 빨리..
We will.
We both will --
미안해, 엘
가봐야 겠어
Sorry, El. Got to go.
응. 빚진 거야
Okay.
Well, you owe me.
응. 사랑해
Okay. Love you.
왜 가로막으신 거에요?
Why'd you cut me off?
음, 그냥 사건에 대해서
엘과 네가 얘기하는게 싫어서 말야
Well, I just didn't want you
talking with El about the case.
오, 켈러에 대해서 언급하는게
싫으신 거죠?
Oh. By "the case," you mean you
don't want me to mention Keller?
내가 그 사건을 맡고 나서
꽤 짜증을 냈었어
She got pretty riled up
after I was taken.
켈러란 이름을 알릴 필요는 없잖아
There's no need to mention
Keller's name to her
아직 그가 어딨는지도 모르는데 말야
when we don't even know yet
if he's on the continent.
아. 저기 라켈이군
Ahh. There's Raquel.
마피아들이 돌아다니는 곳을 좋아하는 구만
Love how she picked
a mob hangout.
이 도시에서 가장 안전한 카페죠
Safest cafe in the city.
여기서 오래 있지 않을 생각인것 같은데
헤일과 연락하는 방법은 없나?
She won't stay here long.
Any way of contacting Hale?
- 메시지를 남겼었죠
- 구식이군
I paged him.
Old school.
맞아요. 좋아하실 걸요
Yeah. You'd like him.
음
Mm.
그녀를 놓치고 싶진 않아
켈러와의 유일한 연관고리 잖아
I don't want to lose her.
She's our only link to Keller.
헤일이 이미 준비를 해놨어요
Hale's already
laid the groundwork.
절 만난다는 걸 알고 있을 거에요
She knows she's meeting me.
제가 접근을 하고나면
우리를 급습 하세요
Let me make the approach.
Then you try to bust us.
요원님의 악마의 손길에서
벗어난다면 믿음을 살 수 있죠
Once we successfully
evade your evil clutches,
I'll gain her confidence.
그게 계획 인거지?
That's a plan.
내가 둘다 잡은 담에
Or...You make the approach,
I arrest both of you,
엄한 심문을 하고
풀어 주라는 거지
and release you two together
after a grueling interrogation.
그럼 네가 배신하지 않았다는걸
그녀가 보고 난 뒤
When she sees
you didn't flip on her,
너에 대한 믿음을 더 가질꺼고
she'll embrace you
in her evil circle of trust.
네. 초기 관계를 형성하는 데엔
'승리'의 경험이 더 좋죠
Yeah. Early in a relationship,
it's better to experience a win.
좋아, 잘 들어
Okay. Tell you what.
네가 FBI 요원이고
내가 연방 교도소 시스템의 간수라면
When you're an FBI agent
and I'm the ward
of the federal prison system,
네 방법대로 할텐데 말야
we'll do it your way.
항상 전 우리가 파트너라고 생각했는데요
All this time,
I thought we were partners.
파트너 맞아.
단지 넥타이처럼 나와 함께하는 거지
We are. It's just,
tie always goes to me.
You ready?
준비 됬어?
그럼요. 보스
You're the boss.
다이애나, 닐이 접근 중이다
Diana, Neal's
making his approach.
"내 마음을 예찬하고
내 마음을 예찬한다"
"Hail my heart.
Hail my heart.
"내 변화를 예찬한다"
Hail my transformation."
"죽음의 책", 챕터 30B
Book of the Dead, Chapter 30B.
감동인데
I'm impressed.
최근에 이집트 국립 방물관에서 사라진
3500년 된 풍뎅이 부적의 뒤쪽에 써져 있죠
It's inscribed on the back
of a 3,500-year-old
scarab amulet
recently removed from
the Egyptian National Museum.
아직 헤일이 오지도 않았는데, 알고 있네
You know that, and yet no Hale.
우리의 오랜 친구가 말해선
안될 것 까지 말한 것 같은데
Our friend told you
a lot more than he should have.
저를 믿으니까요
He trusts me.
그는?
Then where is he?
나타날 겁니다
He'll show.
고마워요
Thank you.
조각을 보여 주시겠어요?
May I see the piece?
첫 만남 부터 그걸 가지고
왔으리라 생각하는 거?
You think I'd bring it
on a first date?
반 쯤은 널 죽이고 싶은
마음이 있거든
I still have half a mind
to kill you.
그러지 않아서 다행이네요
I'd rather you didn't.
하지만 그러신다면..
But if you do...
그 전에 잃어버린 파라오의 부적을
꼭 보고 싶군요
...I'd really like to see
the amulet of the lost pharaoh
before I go.
이것부터 시작해 보는건?
Why don't we start with this?
이집트 도자기라..
Egyptian faience...
부서진 석영으로 이루어졌고
Composed of crushed quartz,
모래, 방해석, 석회
그리고 알카리성이네요
sand, calcite, lime,
and alkalis.
중후기 왕국 샵티의 사후를 보호하기 위해
파라오와 함께 묻은 거지
I'd describe it
as a late-middle-kingdom shabti,
buried with the pharaohs
to protect them in an afterlife.
중기 왕국이 아니에요
It's not middle kingdom.
현대 석고 반죽에
높은 칼슘 함류랑으로
The plaster's modern, and
it has a higher calcium content,
안에 뭐가 들어있든지 간에
그걸 지키려고 했네요
probably to protect
whatever's inside it.
어떤게 안에 들어있는지
알기는 아주 어려워
It's very hard
to get to what's inside.
오후에 복원 작업을 할 수 있을것 같군요
I could put together a restoring
process in an afternoon.
네 자신감과 열정이 마음에 들어
I like your confidence
and your passion.
하지만 아직
헤일이랑 얘기해봐야겠어
But I still
need to talk to Hale.
그 전까진..
Until then.
알려지지 않은 것들에 대해
이야기 해보죠
We're both walking
into the unknown without Hale.
때때로는 직감을 믿어보는 것도 좋아요
But sometimes
you trust your instinct.
내 직감은 도망가라고 하는데
My instinct says walk away.
친구들을 데려온 것 같군요
I see you brought company.
- FBI
- 맞아요. 뭐 걸릴 거 있나요?
The feds.
Yeah. What's our story?
샵티 공항에 데려다 주기 전까진 말 안해
I'm not talking to them.
Not with Airport Shabti on me.
좋아요
All right.
빠져나가죠. 어서요
I'll get us out of here.
Come on.
FBI, FBI 급습, 급습
Feds. FBI raid. Raid.
FBI? 무슨말 하는거요?
FBI. What's he
talking about?
FBI? 어디?
Feds? Where?
Whoa, whoa. What is this?
여기서 점심 먹으려던 참이오
I'm trying to have
a nice lunch here.
- 파스타 먹는 중이었단 말이오
- 당신 보러 온건 아니에요
I'm in the middle of my rigatoni.
We're not here for you, all right?
그럼 가슈
저 녀석 데리고 가슈
There you go.
Then take me, officer.
저녀석 말고
잊어버리슈
Don't take him.
He's nobody. Forget him.
뭐? 입다물고 있어
Nobody?
Watch your mouth.
넥타이 하지 말껄 그랬네
The tie
was supposed to go to me.
꽤 쓸모있는데
You're resourceful.
팀 작업이죠
당신이 카페를 골랐잖아요
Team effort.
You picked the cafe.
내 마지막 파트너는
Still,
my last partner --
- 파트너?
- 복원 기술자
Partner?
Restoration tech.
이집트에서 유물들 주변을
둘러싸는 틀을 만들었어
He created the molds
around these pieces in Egypt.
무슨 일이 벌어진거죠?
What happened to him?
글쎄, 너 만큼 쓸모있진 않았어
Well, he wasn't
as resourceful as you are.
이집트 감옥에서 오랫동안 있어야 할거야
He'll be in an Egyptian prison
for a long time.
그가 잡히기 전에 그 부적도
같이 보냈으면 좋았을 텐데요
Well, at least he shipped you the
amulet before he was arrested.
그도 그렇게 말했어
틀을 제거하기 전까진 알 수 없지
So he says. No way of knowing
until we unwrap it.
택시
Taxi.
시간 비워놔
Keep your schedule open.
시간과 장소를 알려줄게
I'll let you know
when and where.
연락은 어떻게 하나요?
How can I get in touch?
할 수 없어
You can't.
먼지 털지 말고, 웃지 마
No, no. No dusting off.
No smiling.
소리 없이 활짝 웃으며 오지 말라고
Don't come in here
with a grin on your face.
하지만 왔는데요
But I'm in.
그래, 계획은 FBI로
데리고 오는 거였잖아
Yeah, but the plan was
for me to haul you and her in
to the FBI.
저도 그 계획은 괜찮았어요
I was good with that plan.
근데 넌 "FBI 급습"
이라고 외쳐댔잖아
And yet you yelled,
"FBI raid."
들어보세요, 그녀는 유물을 가지고 있었다구요
Look, she had an artifact
on her.
라켈은 자수할 생각이 없었어요
Raquel wasn't
about to turn herself in.
오. 라켈? 흠
Oh. Raquel, huh? Hmm.
- 왜요?
- 아냐
What?
Oh, nothing.
신비하고, 멋진데다가
모자도 썼었지
Mysterious, gorgeous,
she wears a hat.
섹시한 분야에서는
그녀가 특별한 전문가 인가보네
She's an expert
in a certain subject
that you find
particularly sexy.
무슨 말씀 하시는거에요?
What are you talking about?
그냥 날 왜 버렸는지 궁금해서 말야
Just wondering
why you ditched me.
말씀 드렸잖아요, 요원님
그녀는 도둑이라구요
I told you, Peter,
she's a thief.
그리고 너도..
And you are...
잡히기 싫은 누군가는 복잡한 레스토랑에서
Someone who escaped
your capture
두 단어를 말해야 하겠죠
"FBI 급습"
in a crowded restaurant by
saying two words -- "FBI raid."
장난 치지 말고
Don't get cocky.
- 전화 좀 받아도 될까요?
- 그래
May I?
Yes, you may.
모즈에요
It's Moz.
무슨 일이야?
헤일이 오늘 나타나지 않았어
What's going on?
Hale didn't show today.
닐, 이유가 있었어
Neal, he had a reason.
그게 뭔데?
What is it?
헤일이 죽었어
Hale's dead.
유감이야, 모즈
I'm sorry, Moz.
헤일은 적이 없었어
Hale didn't have any enemies.
그는 마지막으로 남은
신사적인 장물아비였어
He was the last
of the gentleman fences.
무슨 일인지 찾아낼거야
We'll find out what happened.
누가 이 일을 저질렀는지
증거가 나오나요?
They have any idea
who did this?
지문도, 혈은도 아무것도 없어
No fingerprints,
no blood splatter, nothing.
보안 장비는 확인했나요?
Did you check
the security feed?
- 보안 장비?
- 네, 설치 했었어요
Security feed?
Yeah, he installed it.
왜 아무에게도 말 안한거야?
Why didn't you tell anyone?
- 말 하려 했어요
- 어떻게 하면 되지?
I tried to.
What do you need?
노트북과 USB 케이블을 주세요
All I need is a laptop
and a USB cable.
서두르세요, 여러분
Ticktock, everyone.
장비는 소리에 동작하도록
되어있어서
The feed is sound-activated.
누군가와 말 할때만 녹음 됩니다
It only records
when someone's talking.
내가 그 작품을 가지고 있을수도 있지
I might have
that piece of art for you.
나중에 이야기 하지
Talk to you later.
나가
Get out.
켈러
Keller.
- 괜찮나?
- 네
You okay?
Yeah.
켈러가 헤일을 어떻게 알고 있던 거지?
How did Keller know Hale?
몰랐을 거에요.
그랬다면 제가 알았겠죠
He didn't.
I would have known if he did.
헤일의 죽음은 어떻게든
라켈과 부적에 관련이 있을거야
So Hale's death
is somehow connected
to Raquel and the amulet.
뭔가 다른 일이 아니라면 말이지
Unless it's something else.
요원님, 저도 알고 싶어요
Peter, I wish I knew.
이 작전을 중지해야겠어
I'm shutting down
this operation.
너와 라켈이 뭔가 진행중인 걸
켈러가 아는 이상 중지해야겠어
I can't take the chance
that Keller knows
that you're going under
with Raquel.
켈러는 우리가 만난걸 몰라요
Keller doesn't know
we've seen him.
그는 차를 처리하려고 생각했을거에요
He thinks he sanitized the car.
라켈과 계속 진행하게 해주세요
Keep me under with Raquel.
헤일의 죽음에 대한 정보를
더 얻기 전까지는 안돼
No, not until I know more
information on how Hale died.
그때 쯤이면 라켈을
놓칠 수도 있다구요, 요원님
We may lose her by then, Peter.
이게 켈러의 계획이라면
If this is Keller's plan,
라켈이 그를 이끌어낼 수 있는
최고의 방법이에요
Raquel is the best way
to draw him out.
좋아
Okay.
켈러를 멈추게 하고 싶어
I want Keller stopped.
새라
Sara.
새라 엘리스, 맞죠?
Sara Ellis, right?
도와드릴까요?
May I help you?
네, 인터폴의
슬로건 요원입니다
Yeah.
Agent Sloan, Interpol.
닐 카프리와 이야기 하고 싶군요
We need to talk
about Neal Caffrey.
죄송하지만, 오늘은 좋은 날이 아닌 것 같습니다.
다음에 다시 얘기하시죠
I'm sorry. Today's not a good day,
so perhaps some other time.
안됩니다
Afraid not.
그리고 전..
And, uh...
보물에 대해서 알고 있습니다
I know about the treasure.
실례합니다만, 뭐라고 하신 거죠?
Excuse me?
I don't follow.
왜 그러시나요, 새라
Come on, Sara.
새라라 불러도 되죠?
Can I call you Sara?
아니요
No.
이봐요, 적대적일 필요는 없다구요
Look, this doesn't
have to be antagonistic.
우린 계속 카프리를 쫓아 왔습니다
We've been following
Mr. Caffrey
빈센트 애들러의 죽음에 둘러쌓인
수상쩍은 사건이 벌어진 이후로 말이죠
ever since we learned
of the suspicious events
surrounding
Vincent Adler's death.
화재와 침몰만이
공개적으로 알려진 거지만
The fire and the sub,
that's public knowledge,
닐 카프리가 사치스러운 생활을
하고 있더군요
but...Neal Caffrey's extravagant
lifestyle while serving time
그 보물 창고에 작은 빛을
비추는데 도움을 줬으면 하는데 말이죠
is something we think
you can help shed some light on.
글쎄요, 카프리와 전 더 이상
만나는 사이가 아니에요
Well, Neal Caffrey and I
are no longer seeing each other,
그러니, 잘못 찾아오셨네요
so we're not in contact.
이봐요, 그건 새로운 소식인데
See, that is news,
저번 아침에 둘이
같이 있는걸 봤는데 말이요
'cause we saw you two together
the other morning.
여기 있군요
헬리콥터를 사고 있지
There you both are, what,
purchasing four helicopters.
그 누가 4대의 헬리콥터를 구입하겠소?
What does one do
with four helicopters?
스털링 보쉬사는 도둑질에 대해서
꽤 엄한 규칙을 적용하고 있더군요
Sterling-Bosch
has some pretty strict rules
about theft recovery, Sara.
당신의 상관이, 국제적인 수사에
대해서 언급하지 않던가요?
Your boss,
has he mentioned anything
about an internal
investigation?
- 아니요
- 그렇겠죠
No.
That's right.
내가 아직 그에게 언급하지
않았으니 말이죠
Probably because I haven't
mentioned this case to him yet.
음. 사실 무슨 말 하시는지 모르겠네요
Well, I honestly
don't know what to tell you.
그래, 그렇겠죠
Yeah, you do.
그냥 내게 '뭔가' 말해요
Just give me something.
뭔가 말해주면, 아마도 닐이
가벼운 형랑을 받을지도 모르죠
Give me something, and maybe
Neal skates on a light sentence.
그렇지 않으면, 카프리가
힘들어 질거고
But if not,
Caffrey goes down hard,
당신을 범죄 방조자로
충분히 만들수 있죠
and I've got enough
to make you an accessory.
간단한 정보 일부만 주면되요, 새라
Simple piece
of information, Sara.
당신 선택에 달렸소
It's your choice.
감사합니다
최선을 다하겠습니다
Thank you very much.
We'll do our best.
감사합니다
Appreciate it.
중요해 보이는 분들인데요
They look important.
이집트 대사관에서 온 사람들이야
무슨 일이야?
From the Egyptian Embassy.
What do you have?
라켈에게서 연락이 왔어요
Heard from Raquel.
그래, 만나기로 한 시간은?
So, when is the rendezvous?
내일 2시
그녀의 연구소에요
2:00 tomorrow.
Her lab.
좋아, 근처에서 잠복 하고
휴대폰을 도청할꺼야
Good. We've got her place staked
out, and her phone's tapped.
켈러에 대한 단서는 더 없나요?
No more leads on Keller?
없어, 하지만 아무것도
기대 안한건 아냐
No. But I wasn't
expecting any.
엘리자베스에게 뭔가 말하길 원하신다면
Listen, you may want
to say something to El
켈러가 돌아온다는게 확실해진
지금이 좋을거에요
now that we're sure
Keller's back.
닐 카프리가 파트너 사이에서는
비밀이 없어야 한다고 말하는거야?
Neal Caffrey suggests
that someone shouldn't keep
secrets from their partner.
어디서 들은거야?
Where's this coming from?
비밀이 많은 누군가에게서요
Someone who keeps
a lot of secrets.
그래
Yeah.
켈러를 잡으러 가죠
Let's nail Keller this time.
그러자
Let's.
닐은 어딨어?
Where's Neal?
오, 반가워요
Oh. Hello to you, too.
모지
지금 중요한 상황이야
No, Mozzie.
This is important.
- 전화 해봤나요?
- 할 수 없어
Did you try calling him?
I can't.
하기 싫은거에요, 아님 휴대폰의
다이얼을 누를 수 없는 거에요?
You don't want to,
or you're not
physically capable
of dialing a telephone?
좋아, 여기 아직 도청 탐지기가
작동 하고 있지?
Okay, do you still
sweep this place for bugs?
이 벽 안에선 자유롭게 얘기해도 되죠
What do you think? You may speak
freely within these walls.
보물에 대해서 알아
I know about the treasure.
어떤 보물?
What treasure?
- 모지, 닐의 노트북에서 봤어
- 오, 젠장
Mozzie, I saw it on Neal's laptop.
Oh, damn it.
당신과 함께 섬으로 도망치길 원했는데
닐이 말했군요
He wants you to run away to the island with us.
So Neal told you.
- 닐이 얘기하진 않았어
- 오, 그럼 '내가' 얘기 한건가요?
He didn't tell me.
Oh. Did I tell you?
모지, 닐을 쫓는 인터폴
요원이 있었어
Mozzie, there is an Interpol
agent who is on to you and Neal.
몇 주 동안 날 따라왔고
He has been following me
for weeks,
보물에 대해서도 알고 있어
and he knows
about the treasure.
뭔가 얘기 했나요?
Did you tell him anything?
뭔가는 말해야 했다고
Well, I had to
give him something.
오, 자신을 보호하기 위해 말이죠
Oh, to protect yourself.
아니, 우리 모두를 보호하기 위해 말야
No, to protect all of us.
우리 전부를 연루 시키려고 하고있어
He was gonna drag us all in.
닐이 정말 내게 모든걸
말하려고 했단 말이야?
Neal was really
gonna tell me everything?
맞아요, 하지만 내가
Yes, but I talked him out of it
이런 일이 벌어질까봐
말하지 말라고 했었죠
for the exact reason that
you're standing here right now.
요원에게 뭘 말한 거에요?
What did you tell the agent?
닐과 네가 연관되어있다고
말하진 않았지만
I never said
that you two were involved,
보물 감시 카메라의
IP 주소를 알려줬어
but I had to give him the I.P. address
for the treasure-cam.
- 얼마나 됬죠?
- 몰라, 난..
How long ago?
I don't know. I --
- 얼마나 됬나구요?
- 40분 정도?
How long?
40 minutes ago.
비밀번호를 주진 않았어
I didn't give him the password.
쉽게 해킹 당하진 않을꺼라 생각했어
I assumed it wasn't
easily hacked.
당신이 인터폴이 아닌 이상
U-unless you're Interpol!
장비를 꺼버려야겠어요
I-I have to shut down
the feed.
음, 슬로건 요원에 대해서
이미 알고 있었네
Well, you already know
about agent Sloan.
- 이 사람이 당신이 만난사람이에요?
- 맞아
That's who you met?
Yeah.
- 이 사람에게 IP 주소를 주었구요?
- 모지, 왜 그래?
And you gave him the I.P. address?
Mozzie, what?
이 사람이 바로 닐이
죽길 원하는 사람이에요
It's the one man
who wants Neal dead.
모지, 무슨 일이야?
Hey, Mozzie, what's going on?
켈러가 인터폴 요원으로 위장하고 있어
Keller's been posing
as an Interpol agent.
- 새라를 만났고 말야
- 뭐?
He met with Sara.
What?
새라는 그가 누군지 몰랐어
She had no idea who he was.
새라는 괜찮은거야?
Is she okay?
그래, 하지만 IP 주소를
알려줘 버렸어
Yes, but she did
give up the I.P. address.
안돼
No.
감시 카메라를 재설정 했어
I reset the feed.
- 안전한거야?
- 지금은 안전해
Is it secure?
It is now.
좋아. 만약 그가 화면을 봐버렸다면
보물이 진짜란 걸 알게될꺼야
All right. If he's seen the feed,
he knows the treasure is real.
켈러가 언뜻 그걸 봤더라도
Look -- even if Keller
did get a glimpse of it,
창고를 추척 해 낼
방법은 없을꺼야
there's no way he could trace it
back to the warehouse.
내 캔버스의 견본이 화재에서
살아 남았던 것처럼 말야?
Like there's no way
a swatch of my canvas
could have survived the fire?
켈러를 유린할 백업 플랜을 실행할거야
I'm going to put a backup plan
for Keller into place.
넌 미술품들의 보안만 신경써
내가 켈러를 맡을게
You take care of securing the art.
I'll handle Keller.
안돼, 안돼
No, no, no, no.
켈러를 완전히
멈추게 만들꺼야, 알았지?
I'm gonna stop Keller
once and for all, okay?
닐?
Neal?
니..
Ne--
고마워요
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
여기
Here you go.
존스, 더 이상 이런 만남은 그만하죠
Jones, we have to
stop meeting like this.
그거 지금 모든 요원들한테
전달 된거야
I bet you say that
to all the agents.
도청 탐지기로 스캔할 때만 꺼놔
Turn it off
only if she sweeps for bugs.
- 1분 이상 연락이 되지 않으면 들어갈게
- 네
If I lose contact with you
for more than a minute, I'm coming in.
Got it.
- 그리고 오늘의 비밀번호는
- 인스크립션(inscription)
And the password
for the day is... inscription.
그럴 가능성은 없지만
간단히 처리해
No chances.
Keep it simple.
그게 풍뎅이 부적이라는 걸
알아차리는 순간
The instant you know
it's the real scarab amulet,
바로 연락해
you call us in.
갈게요
Here we go.
안녕하세요
Hello.
잠깐
Not so fast.
내 탐지 막대기
My wand.
당신이 혼자라는걸 확신하게 해주지
To make sure we're alone.
물론
Of course.
아주 빠른데
Well, that was fast.
조금 있으면 다시 연결 될겁니다
He'll come back online.
50초 후에, 들어간다
In 50 seconds, we move in.
아주 좋아
Very nice.
그렇게 아프진 않네요
Wasn't so painful.
이거 아니었으면
누드상태로 일 해야 했겠지
Without it,
we'd have to work in the nude.
고대 영혼의 소리인가요?
Ancient spirits?
에어컨 소리
Air conditioner.
이것도 그 나름의 삶이 있어
It has a life of its own.
이게 바로 해결하고 싶은거야
돌아 왔습니다
- This is what I want you to see.
- He's back.
8초 더 늦었으면
들어 갈 뻔 했어
In 8 seconds,
I was gonna move in.
켈러가 저길 쳐들어 가길 기대해야겠네
We can expect Keller to strike
in a window that small.
천재적이군요
Genius.
20 달러짜리 문진으로 보이는데요
(paperweight : 종이를 누르는데 쓰이는 물건)
Looks like a $20 paperweight.
Let's hope it's not.
그렇지 않길 바라지
조심해
Be careful with it.
그건 특별한거야
This one's special.
용서하세요, 신부님
막 죄를 저지르려는 참입니다
Bless me, father,
for I'm about to sin.
우리 모두가 그렇지
We all are.
날 찾아 냈구만
무엇을 원하나?
You found me.
What do you want?
문제를 푸는데 도움이 필요합니다
I need your help
with a problem.
매튜 켈러
600만 달러?
Matthew Keller.
$6 million?
제 친구를 죽였습니다
He killed a friend of mine.
이젠 제 근처에 있는
사람까지 위협하고 있습니다
Now he's threatening
others close to me.
이건 큰 일이구만
This is a lot.
특별히 일처리를 담당할
녀석을 생각해 두었나?
You got a particular
client in mind for the job?
모두에게 연락해 주십시오
켈러 '사냥 허가' 기간입니다
Contact all of them.
It's open season on Keller.
전리품은 승자에게 돌아갈겁니다
Spoils go to the victor.
주소는 있나?
You got an address?
그들이 돈을 벌도록 나두십시오
Let your people
earn their money.
알아서 찾아 낼겁니다
They can find him.
그래. 헌금 접시엔
뭔가 남기고 가도록
Yeah. Leave something
in the collection plate.
어떻게 되는지 보시죠
Let's see how this works.
에어컨이 동작하지 않네
The A.C. isn't working.
끄고 올게
I'm gonna shut it off.
좀 더워도 괜찮지?
Can you survive a little sweat?
뉴욕의 여름은 스릴있죠
It's the thrill
of New York in the summer.
보세요
Look at this.
하이로그래픽스가 써져있네요
(hieroglyphics: 상형 문자로 된 글)
You can see the hieroglyphics
indented in the mold.
아름 다운 언어지
It's a beautiful language.
사실 이건 예술이죠
It's an art, really.
파피루스의 일곱개 스크롤에
대해서 들어 봤어요?
You ever heard of
the papyrus seven scrolls?
물론
Of course.
그게 위조란게 밝혀져서
애석하긴 하지만
It's a shame they were
proven to be forgeries.
다수의 이집트 학자가
평가하기 전까진 말이죠
Only after a dozen different
egyptologists weighed in.
알아. 내가 그중 한명이었거든
I know.
I was one of them.
그것들은 잘 만들어진 예술품이었지
Those were a work of art.
너였어?
That was you?
그럴리 없어
No.
추측이란게 존재하죠
There is that speculation.
위조범, 복원 기술자
A forger, a restoration tech,
탈출한 예술가라
an escape artist.
와우
Wow.
함께 할 수 있는게
더 있겠는데
The things
we could do together.
어서, 닐
그냥 망할 부적을 찾아내
Come on, Neal.
Just uncover the damn amulet.
여깄네요
And there it is.
이걸 위해 내 생을 걸고 기다렸어
I've waited for this one
my entire career.
실제 보물을 발견하는
짜릿함을 느껴본적이 있어?
Have you ever
experienced the thrill
of discovering a real treasure?
좋아
움직일 준비 하자고
All right.
Let's get ready to move in.
카프리가 몇 분내로
신호를 줄꺼야
Caffrey should
give us the signal any minute.
지금 그걸 기대하고 있죠
I'm experiencing it now.
준비들 하라구
Let's suit up.
적힌 글을 읽을 수 있나요?
You read the inscription?
우리가 만날 아름다운 장소로
나와 있었구만
"You have come forth
to the beautiful place
to which we run."
그거 놀랍지 않은가?
It's remarkable, isn't it?
누구시죠?
Who are you?
매튜 켈러
Matthew Keller.
닐의 오랜 친구지
I'm an old friend of Neal's.
어떤 일이 있긴 했지만
친구는 절대 아니었어요
We were something,
but we were never friends.
그럼 내가 이집트 박물관에서
부적을 훔친 사람이라 생각하는 구만
Then think of me as the man
who stole that amulet
from the Egyptian Museum.
당신이 그랬어요?
You?
인상적이지 않은가?
Impressive, huh?
지금 다시 돌려 받고 싶단 말이지
Now I kind of want it back.
뭘 걱정하나?
What are you worried about?
밴에 타고 있는 녀석들은
걱정 하지 말라고
Don't worry
about the boys in the van.
FBI는 오지 않아
The feds ain't coming.
FBI?
Feds?
추측해 보건데,
아직 말 안했구만?
Oh, let me guess.
He didn't tell you?
저 녀석은 FBI의
범죄 컨설턴트지
Yeah, he's a criminal
consultant for the FBI.
그렇지, 친구?
Right, buddy?
넌 닐 카프리..
You're Neal Caffrey.
이거 봐
넌 유명하다고
Well, look at that.
You're famous.
라켈, 이 사람은
정말 위험해요
Raquel, this man
is incredibly dangerous.
저 사람이 말한건
아무것도 믿지 마세요
Don't believe
anything he tells you.
내가 말하려는 것 중
일부라도 잘 들어야 할텐데
You should listen
to some things I tell you.
오, 헤이!
Oh! Hey!
흥미로워 지는데?
This is spicy, huh?
둘 사이에 뭔가 있는지는
모르겠지만
I don't know what's going on
between you two,
여기 계속 머무르지는 않아야겠네
but I'm not sticking around
to find out.
좋은 생각이구만, 자기
이건 그냥 남자들 이야기야
That's a good idea, sweetheart.
This is just guy talk.
사내 들이 그렇지 뭐
Boys will be boys.
라켈
Raquel.
널 믿었었는데
I trusted you.
아름다워 보이는구만
She seems nice.
뭘 원하지?
What do you want?
왜 그러나, 닐
Come on, Neal.
난 보물을 원해
I want the treasure.
당신이 이걸 꾸몄군
You set this up.
당신이 보석을 훔치고
라켈의 복원 기술자를
You stole the amulet
and had Raquel's restorer
이집트 감옥에 잡아넣었고
그녀는 새 사람이 필요해진거군
arrested in Egypt
so she'd need someone new.
이 일이 벌어지기 전에
알아채지 못해서 안됬구만
Too bad you didn't
put that together before now.
누군가 켈러에게 돈을 걸었어요?
Someone put a hit on Keller?
그래. 큰 건이야.
600 만 달러
Yeah.
Big one. $6 million.
얼마요?
How much?
록키, 거리를 유지하고 있어
Rockie, keep your distance.
그 사람은 지금 제 연구소에 있어요
He's at my place right now.
아직 이 일에 끼어들
좋은 시점은 아니야
This is not the time
for you to be getting into this.
그가 내게 빚진거네요
No. He owes me.
창고에 뭔가 꽤 중요한게
있는것 같던데
Must be something pretty
important in that warehouse.
밝혀졌어, 닐
Turns out, Neal,
절대 발견되지 않을
최고의 보물들을 놓아두었다는 거
you're sitting on one
of the greatest treasures
never discovered.
난 보물을 가지고 있지 않아
I don't have a treasure.
너한테 없다는건 알지
I know you don't.
내게 있거든
I do.
에어컨 소리야
That's the air conditioner.
- 존스
- 네?
- Jones.
- Yeah?
에어컨 켠다는 소리는 안했지?
Didn't she say
she turned off the A.C.?
네, 그런것 같습니다
Yeah, I thought so.
오디오 뒤로 돌려봐
Play back the audio.
에어컨이 동작하지 않네
끄고 올게
- The A.C. isn't working.
- I'm gonna shut it off.
좀 더워도 괜찮지?
Can you survive a little sweat?
뉴욕의 여름은 스릴있죠
The thrill of New York
in the summer.
- 에어컨을 껐다네요
- 지금 오디오가 반복 되는거야
She shut it off.
We're on on audio loop.
모든 요원에게 알린다
실제로 가 봐야겠다
All agents, I want a visual.
빌딩을 둘러싸도록
들어 간다
Surround the building.
We're moving in.
내가 찾은게 뭔지 와서 봐바
Come see what I found.
여기 있지
There it is.
이걸 알아차렸을 때의
네 얼굴을 보고 싶었어
I wanted to see your face
when you figured it out.
내가 이겼어, 닐
I won, Neal.
총성이 울렸다!
Shots fired!
저리가, 카프리
Distance, Caffrey.
젠장
Damn it.
너도 알다시피, 넌 자랑스러워 해도 돼
You know, you should be proud.
헤일은 내게 드가에 대한
정보를 주기 싫어했거든
Hale -- he didn't want to give
up the knowledge on the Degas.
그리고 새라
And Sara --
귀여운 새라
네가 마음을 아프게한
Pretty little Sara,
whose heart you broke --
그녀도 널 배신하지 않았지
She didn't want
to betray you, either.
축하해
Congratulations.
친구들을 만들었구나
You made friends.
당신을 꼭 쓰러트리고 말겠어
I can't wait to take you down.
FBI다! 문열어!
FBI! Open up!
그들의 시간인것 같군
They took their time.
닐!
Neal!
오, 부적
위로의 선물이야
Oh, the amulet.
Consolation prize.
닐!!
Neal!
요원님, 저에요!
혼자 있고, 무기는 없어요
Peter, it's Neal!
I'm alone and unarmed, okay?
문 열게요
I'm unlocking the door.
어떻게 되가는거야?
What's going on?
켈러가 여기 있었어요
무기를 들고 있어요
Keller was here.
He's armed.
뭐? 어디로 갔어?
What?
Where'd he go?
저 문으로요
That door.
윗층을 확인하겠습니다
I'll check upstairs.
뭔가 있나?
Anything?
없습니다
Clear.
- 존스?
- 없습니다
Jones?
Clear.
대체 어디로 간거야?
Where the hell did he go?
존스, 카프리를 잡아
Jones, get Caffrey.
쥐구멍이네요
A rabbit hole.
그래
여기로 나갔구만
Yeah.
That's where he went.
요원님
Peter.
사라졌습니다
He's gone.
추적장치가 없는 상태에요
He's off anklet.
찾아
Find him.
좋아, 거의 창고에 다 왔어
All right,
I'm almost at the warehouse.
확실한 계획이 필요해, 모즈
We need a solid plan, Moz.
좋아
실행 중이야
Okay.
It's coming up.
기다려, 닐
Wait. Neal.
왜?
What is it?
지금 창고에 있진 않아
He's not in the warehouse.
잠간. 이미 떠난거야?
뭘 가져갔어?
Wait. His men are gone?
What did they take?
기다려봐
다른걸 확인해볼게
Hold on.
Let me check something.
예전 화면을 볼게
Let me look at the old feed.
좋아
Yes.
그들은 '거기' 말고 '거기'에 있어
They're there,
but they're not there there.
무슨 말 하는거야?
What are you saying?
가짜 창고야
It's a fake warehouse.
지금 카메라에 잡힌건
우리 보물이 아니야
The treasure room on cam --
it's not ours.
켈러가 예전 주소를 해킹한게 틀림없어
Keller must have hacked
the feed.
그가 우릴 속인거라고?
He faked it?
신호를 따라 실제 위치를
알아내진 못한 것 같아
Apparently he couldn't
follow the signal
to the real location,
그가 복제품을 만든 것 같아
so he made a replica.
그게 켈러가 내게 나타나 진짜 창고로
이끌도록 한 이유구나
And the only reason
he showed up at the lab
was to get me to lead him
to the real warehouse.
- 추적 장치 없이 말야
- 젠장
Off anklet.
Damn it.
FBI는 네가 지금 어디있는지 모를꺼야
The FBI has no idea
where you are,
널 제거하려 들꺼야
so he can take you down.
미행 당하고 있어?
Are you being followed?
아마도
Maybe.
좋아.
좋은 생각이 있어
All right.
I got an idea.
다른 장소로 그를 유인해서
Lead him someplace else,
FBI가 올 때까지 거기 숨어있는거지
and then hide there
until help arrives.
바로 그거야
주변에 뭐가 있어?
Exactly.
What's around here?
음..
Um...
좋아, 팰리스가 있어
Okay, uh --
The palace.
팰리스라
거기 좋아하는 곳인데
The palace.
Always a fan favorite.
신부님
Uh, father.
유용하게 쓰일 주소를 알고 있습니다
I have an address
that you will find useful.
팰리스라고 들어보셨나요?
Have you ever heard of
the palace?
요원님, 카프리의 GPS 가 돌아왔습니다
Hey. Caffrey's GPS
is back on.
- 어디야?
- 비크맨 가 5번지 입니다
Where is he?
5 Beekman.
가자
Let's go.
어서, 카프리
Come on, Caffrey.
보물을 최상층에 숨겨 놓은건
아니란걸 알아
I know you're not keeping
the loot on an upper level.
이 건물 안에 보물을
숨겨 놓진 않았어
I'm not keeping the loot
in this building.
별로 예상하기 어렵진 않은데
너도 알잖아?
You're as predictable
as everyone else, you know that?
네 소중한 화물들을 옮길 때
The moment you saw your precious
cargo had been hauled away,
FBI를 피해서
내게 바로 인도해 줬지
you dodged the feds
and led me right to it.
아님 내가 당신의 계획을
알아 차렸을지도
Or I figured out your plan...
대신 여기로 데리고 왔을 수도 있지
Brought you here instead.
그렇게 생각하진 않는데
어딨는지 말해
Yeah, I don't think so.
Show me where it is.
이번 건은 함께 하자고, 허?
Let's just work together
on this one, huh?
어때?
What do you say?
솔직히 말해서, 그게 네가
살아남을 수 있는 유일한 길일텐데 말야
Let's be honest -- it's
your only chance at survival.
피터 요원은 절대 모를꺼야
Peter can't ever know
네가 그의 감시를 피해
보물을 훔쳤다는 걸 말야, 닐
that you stole the goods
from under his nose, Neal.
알게되면 가슴이 찢어지겠지
It'll break his heart.
네 짐을 덜어줄게
So I can help
relieve you of this burden.
그럼 네 범죄 컨설턴트 인생을
계속 할 수 있을거고
You can continue
your criminal-consultant life
여기 뉴욕에서 말야
서로 윈-윈이라는 거지
here in New York --
I mean, it's win-win.
당신도 별로 예상하기 어렵진 않은데, 켈러
You're as predictable
as everyone else, Keller.
당신은 거만하지
Your arrogance.
탐욕스럽고
Your greed.
덫에 걸렸지
You're trapped.
아무도 오지 않아, 닐
Nobody's coming, Neal.
하지만 난 네가 왜 이렇게
But what I can't understand
오랫동안 보물을 나뒀는지는 이해하겠군
is why you would sit
on the treasure for so long.
하나라도 팔게 된다면
I mean, it seems to me
you either sell it,
다시 반납하거나, 도망가야겠구만?
you turn it in,
or you run, right?
아님 FBI가 오고 있거나
내가 보물을 가지고 있지 않을지도
Or the feds are on their way
and I don't have it.
넌 보물을 받을 자격이 없어
You don't deserve it.
보물을 지니고 있어야 할
자격도 없고 말이야
You don't even have
what it takes to hold on to it.
보물이 어디있는지 알고 있는 건
너 뿐만은 아니지
You're not the only one
who knows where it is.
모지에게 '안녕' 이라고 전해줄게
I'll tell Mozzie you said hi.
FBI!!
무기를 내려놔!
FBI!
Drop your weapon.
거짓말 한게 아니야, 켈러
I didn't lie to you, Keller.
난 보물을 가지고 있지 않아
I don't have the treasure.
다시 만나서 반가웠네
버키(Burkey)
It's good to see you again,
Burkey.
저격수 입니다!
Shooter!
켈러는?
Where's Keller?
저기 있어요
There he is.
모두 건물의 북서쪽으로 달아난
용의자를 쫓는다
All units, pursue suspect
on the northwest side
of the building.
저격수를 잡았습니다
I got the shooter.
라켈
Raquel.
왜 도망 간거야?
Why did you run?
말해봐
Talk.
켈러가 도망갔어요
전 그를 쫓고 싶었구요
Keller escaped.
I went after him.
네 옆에 다수의 요원들이 있었어
You had a dozen federal agents
at your side.
오디오 장비와 GPS 는 왜 꺼놨나?
Why did you cut your audio feed
and your GPS?
켈러가 원하는게 뭐였어?
What did Keller want with you?
요원님이 맞았어요
그는 제가 보물을 가지고 있다고 생각했어요
You were right.
He thought I had the treasure.
그리고 팰리스로 그를 이끌었죠
I led him to the palace,
거긴 내가 숨겼을거라
믿을 만한 장소 였어요
the kind of place
he'd believe I'd hide it,
저를 따라 올 수 있게 GPS 를 켜고
I turned on the GPS
so you could follow me --
네가 탈출 하고 난 다음에 말이지
After you escaped.
제가 거기 도착하기 전에
먼저 오셨으면
Otherwise you would have
shown up before I got there.
켈러는 달아났을 거에요
요원님, 먹혔다구요. 잡았잖아요
Keller would have fled.
Peter, it worked. We had him.
그녀가 총을 쏘기 전까진 말야
Until she took a shot at him.
왜 그녀가 총을 쐈는지 모르겠어요
I don't know why she did that.
아마도, 누군가 600만 달러를
포상금으로 걸었기 때문이겠지
Maybe because someone put a $6
million bounty out on Keller.
600만 달러요?
$6 million?
우리만 켈리를 잡길
원한게 아닌 것 같아
I guess we're not
the only ones who want him.
그렇겠죠
Guess not.
들여보내
Bring her in.
다리 들어봐
Give me your foot.
가도 돼
You can go.
날 잡았네, 카프리
You had me, Caffrey.
피터 요원님은 좋은 요원이에요
Look --
Peter's a good agent.
당신이 원했던 것보다 더
켈러를 잡길 원했죠
He wants Keller
more than you do.
그 자식이 내 풍뎅이를 가져갔어
That bastard took my scarab.
또 봐요, 라켈
See you around, Raquel.
앉아
Sit down.
새라
Sara.
여기서 뭐 하는거야?
What are you doing here?
- 피터 요원님이 불렀어
- 오
Peter called me in.
Oh.
내가 켈러를 만난것에 대해
진술 하려고
To make a statement
about my meeting with Keller.
별일 없어서 다행이야
I'm glad you're safe.
모지와 오랬동안 이야기했어
I had a long talk with Mozzie.
네 비밀은 안전해, 닐
Your secret's safe
with me, Neal.
우리 사이를 잊지 않았으면 좋겠어
I hope you don't forget
everything between us.
아니, 다 잊은건 아냐
Well, no.
Not everything.
네가 훔쳐간 라파엘은 잊지 못하지
I won't forget
about that Raphael you stole.
주장한 바에 의하면 말야
Allegedly.
Mm-hmm.
안녕
Hi.
오늘 나쁜 놈들 좀 잡았어?
Did you catch
any bad guys today?
한 쌍
A couple.
다행이네
난 다시 잘게
Oh, good.
I can go back to sleep now.
으흠
Mm-hmm.
침대로 와
Come to bed.
자기야, 괜찮아?
Honey, you okay?
말할 게 있어
There's something
I need to tell you.
응, 듣고 있어
Okay.
I'm listening.
쫓던 놈중 한놈이
도망가 버렸어
One of the guys
we were pursuing --
He got away.
걱정 되는거야?
Are you concerned?
매튜 켈러야
It's Matthew Keller.
뭐? 켈러가 뉴욕에 있어?
What?
Keller's in New York?
자기야, 말하려고 했어
Hon, I was gonna tell you.
왜 말 안한거야?
Why didn't you tell me?
확신이 없었기 때문이야
그를 구석에 몰아 놓은 다음에..
Because we weren't sure.
Then we had him cornered --
자기야, 그 사람은 자길 납치했던 사람이야
Honey, this man
had you kidnapped.
알아. 찾아 낼꺼야
I know.
We're gonna find him.
FBI가 지명 수배자 명단의
최상위에 올려 놓았고
FBI has got him
on the most-wanted list,
미국 보안관들이 총력을 다해서 쫓고있어
the U.S. marshals
are out in full force,
포상금도 걸었고 말야
and there's a bounty
on his head.
말 했어야 했는데..
I should have told you.
미안해
I'm sorry.
이 사건은 맡지마..
Don't do this.
- 지금은 버틸수 있어, 자기도 알잖아
- 알아
I can handle it. You know that.
I know.
하지만 무슨 일이 벌어 지고 난
다음엔 버틸 수 없을꺼야
What I can't handle is finding
out after something happens.
아무일도 벌어지지 않을꺼야
Nothing will.
약속 할게
I promise.
포상금을 걸었다고?
So they have a bounty
on him, huh?
응
Yeah.
이 시점에서 우리가 알고 있는 건
All we know at this point
누군가 600만 달러를 걸어
그가 없어지길 원했다는 거야
is that they're
willing to pay $6 million
to make him go away.
반 다이크, 좋아
The Van Dyck. Good.
마티스
Matisse.
드가
Degas.
드가 어딨지?
Where's the Degas?
모지, 뭘 한거야?
Mozzie, what did you do?
네?
Yeah?
켈러를 잡았어
We arrested Keller.
오?
Oh?
수갑을 채우지는 못했지만 말야
누군가 그를 쐈어
Except as we were cuffing him,
someone shot him.
상처를 입었고
Winged him.
혼란한 틈을 타 도망 쳤어
And in the chaos, he escaped.
오
Oh.
누군가 그의 머리에 포상금을 걸었어
Someone put a bounty
on his head.
600만 달러 포상금이라
A $6 million bounty.
암시장에 드가를 팔았을 때와
비슷한 가격인것 같아
Now, that's roughly
the black-market sale price
of the Degas.
아냐. '정확히' 드가를
팔았을 때의 가격이지
No. That's exactly
the sale price of the Degas.
네가 팔았구나
You fenced it.
내게 물어 봤었어야지
You should have asked me.
그럼, 너도 새라가 창고에 대해서
알고 있다고 말해줬어야지
Well, you should have told me
Sara knew about the warehouse.
지금 보니 우린 비밀을 숨기는
습관이 있는 것 같아
I guess we're in the habit
of keeping secrets now.
네가 켈러에게 포상금을 걸었어?
You took out a hit on Keller?
그가 헤일을 죽였어
He killed Hale.
그리고 새라를 쫓았고
He went after Sara.
널 무너트리기 전 까진
켈러는 멈추지 않으려고 했어
Keller wasn't gonna stop
till he destroys you.
팔지 말라고 했잖아
I told you not to sell it.
모든 준비가 됬었어
다른 걸 팔 여유는 없었다구
It was all set up.
I didn't have time to fence anything else.
그게 목록에 있다고, 모즈!
젠장할 목록에 있다고!
It's on the list, Moz!
It's on the damn list.
뭐?
Excuse me?
어디서 얻었어?
Where did you get this?
피터 요원님의 집에 침입했을 때
목록은 없다고 했잖아
You told me when you
broke into Peter's house
the list wasn't there.
있었어
It was.
거짓말 한거야?
You lied to me?
더 큰 문제가 있어
We got bigger problems,
all right?
드가가 나타나면 FBI는
보물이 타지 않았다는 걸 알게 될꺼야
When the Degas turns up --
and it will --
the FBI is gonna know
the treasure didn't burn.
우리가 주요 용의자라구
And we're the prime suspects.
왜 나한테 말하지 않았어?
Why didn't you tell me?
그건 이제 문제가 아니야
누구에게 팔았어?
Look, it doesn't matter now.
Who did you fence it through?
그걸 다시 돌려받아야 해
We have to get it back.
아님 우린 끝이야, 모즈
Or we're done, Moz.
끝이라구!
We're done.
영어자막 : www.addic7ed.com (honeybunny)
한글자막 : EzLoves